<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Folyo</title>
  <subtitle>The Folyo Blog</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.folyo.me/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.folyo.me/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.folyo.me/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2014-05-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Sacha Greif</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Realigning the Folyo Blog</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/the-folyo-blog-realign/"/>
    <id>/the-folyo-blog-realign/</id>
    <published>2014-05-05T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-05-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sacha Greif</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The web moves fast. Trends like flat design and responsive design didn&amp;rsquo;t even exist a couple years ago. Yet some things can stay surprisingly relevant, even 10 years on. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.cameronmoll.com/"&gt;Cameron Moll&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s article about &lt;a href="http://alistapart.com/article/redesignrealign"&gt;realigning rather than redesigning&lt;/a&gt; is one of those things, and it immediately made sense to me when I first read it,. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all, why throw out all the valuable lessons learned through a previous design when you can build on them and improve something iteratively instead?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this is exactly the approach I chose when it came time to refresh and update this blog. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compare the &lt;a href="http://blog-v1.folyo.me/"&gt;old design&lt;/a&gt; (2011):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=""&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog-v1.folyo.me/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/blog/folyo-blog-old.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;2011&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the new one (2014):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=""&gt;&lt;img src="/images/blog/folyo-blog-new.jpg"/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;2014&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The overall layout and concept stayed the same, but I introduced a lot of small tweaks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Visual Design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most obvious change is the overall aesthetic of the blog. The original was designed before the flat design era, when skeuomorphic realism was all the rage, and it was starting to look extremely dated. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet at the same time, I still liked the “fake notebook” concept, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t want the design to be just one more centered column of text on a white background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I started looking for a different approach. I tweaked the cover of the notebook and the texture of the paper, but I hit a wall when it came to the background. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A dark texture made the site look gloomy, but a light background didn&amp;rsquo;t make the notebook pop out enough. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=""&gt;&lt;a href="http://macdesks.com/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/blog/macdesks.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Mac Desks: showcasing beautiful workplaces.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The breakthrough came while browsing &lt;a href="http://macdesks.com/"&gt;Mac Desks&lt;/a&gt;. If a texture or flat color didn&amp;rsquo;t work, I&amp;rsquo;d use a photo! This gave the design the atmospheric feeling I was looking for, and also inspired the final color scheme. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Typography&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also overhauled the typography. I was previously using &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/fonts/specimen/Open+Sans"&gt;Open Sans&lt;/a&gt;, which is a great font but didn&amp;rsquo;t really match the feeling I was going after. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=""&gt;&lt;img src="/images/blog/abril.jpg"/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Abril Text.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted something elegant yet readable, so a serif font made sense. While browsing Typekit, I finally settled on &lt;a href="https://typekit.com/fonts/abril-text"&gt;Abril Text&lt;/a&gt;, a beautiful face which had the added advantage of being available both as a web and desktop font. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=""&gt;&lt;img src="/images/blog/crete.jpg"/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Crete Rounded.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To complement it, I picked slab serif &lt;a href="https://typekit.com/fonts/crete-rounded-web"&gt;Crete Rounded&lt;/a&gt; for headings. I had been looking for an excuse to use it for a long time, and its solid curves seemed the perfect match for Abril Text&amp;rsquo;s lighter strokes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Responsive Design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first designed the blog in 2011, mobile browsing was on the way up but still represented a minor proportion of traffic. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now in 2014, the situation is of course vastly different. Mobile traffic can&amp;rsquo;t be ignored, and a blog needs to be responsive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I knew it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be easy to “responsify” the site. Responsive design works great for simple designs, but quickly gets tricky when dealing with complex layouts and background images. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ended up using three different breakpoints to deal with the various layouts. The result is a bunch of ugly code, but at least it works!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Simplifying&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also got rid of most of the content in the sidebar. This was both because of my own laziness (simpler is faster!), and also because I personally rarely click sidebar links. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, I decided to put the focus on the newsletter. Email is still the most reliable way of building an audience, so it makes sense to promote it first. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Bye Bye WordPress&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the back-end front, I also got rid of WordPress in favor of &lt;a href="http://middlemanapp.com"&gt;Middleman&lt;/a&gt;, my static site generator of choice. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Switching to a static site greatly simplifies deployment, hosting, and scaling, and also makes development faster. These days, WordPress is probably overkill for the vast majority of blogs, especially if you&amp;rsquo;re comfortable with managing your content through version control. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Make Yourselves at Home&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I&amp;rsquo;ve realized over my years of blogging is that it&amp;rsquo;s very hard for me to write on a blog if I don&amp;rsquo;t like its design. So hopefully, this refreshed design will also encourage me to write more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m also in the process of editing, updating, and republishing the blog&amp;rsquo;s previous articles, so stay tuned for more content soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, take a look around, and let me know what you think!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Common Portfolio Mistakes (And How To Fix Them)</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/common-portfolio-mistakes-and-how-to-fix-them/"/>
    <id>/common-portfolio-mistakes-and-how-to-fix-them/</id>
    <published>2014-04-25T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-04-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sacha Greif</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;!-- *Note: be sure to also check out our quiz on [evaluating your portfolio site's effectiveness](http://blog.folyo.me/folyo-quiz-how-good-is-your-portfolio/)!* --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the curator of Folyo, I see a lot of different portfolios go by. And I can’t help but notice the same patterns of bad design cropping up time and again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being designers, we should be aware of how much look and feel can influence the way content is perceived. Yet for some reason we’re happy to forget all about this when it comes to displaying our own work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know, I know, you just happen to be working on a new version of your portfolio and it’s going to be great, just wait! As soon as you finish that urgent project for that important client, and also learn to use those fancy new CSS3 animations, try out a couple fonts, and maybe also solve world hunger while you’re at it…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stop. None of the problems mentioned in this article take more than a couple hours to fix, yet those simple fixes can have a dramatic impact on your portfolio. So quit procrastinating and read on!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Mistake #1: No Portfolio&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s get this out of the way. Even in this age of blogs, tumblelogs, and social networks, there’s no excuse for not having a portfolio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t force potential clients to sift through your blog to see your work, or hunt you across multiple social networks to get a glimpse of what you’re working on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easy fix: get a free portfolio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s no lack of great portfolio services. They take 15 minutes to set up, and are optimized for showing your work. Here are three very good services which all have free plans:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://dunked.com/"&gt;Dunked&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://cargocollective.com/"&gt;Cargo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://4ormat.com/"&gt;4ormat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And of course, you can also find portfolio themes for Tumblr and Wordpress. Believe me, nobody will care that you haven’t designed your own portfolio as long as the work inside it is great. Here are a few suggestions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wordpress&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://themeforest.net/item/sideshow-funktastic-portfolio-wordpress-theme/550344/?ref=SachaG"&gt;Sideshow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://themeforest.net/item/garnish-cleancut-wordpress-portfolio-theme/308989/?ref=SachaG"&gt;Garnish&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tumblr&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.tumblr.com/theme/8955"&gt;Simplefolio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Mistake #2: Stupid Tagline&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some reason, designers love to feature a huge tagline set in 72px font shouting something like “I create beautiful and usable designs”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Ooh, look at how daring and original I am”, those taglines seem to say, “I’m breaking the mold and making a statement by using 72px Helvetica just like everybody else!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No! Bad designer! Stop!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easy fix: client quote&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These generic cookie-cutter taglines don’t add any value to your site, and don’t tell me anything about you. Instead, why not feature something a real person actually said about you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe something like “Jeff was awesome to work with, he was like a breath of fresh air* after trying out 5 other designers”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boom! In one sentence, you’ve used social proof to convince your potential clients that not only do you do great work, but you’re also better than the competition. What do you say now, Mr Usable Websites?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;* You may or may not draw little clouds around the words “breath of fresh air”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Mistake #3: Painfully Tiny Thumbnails&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Believe it or not, my first portfolio actually had 32px*32px thumbnails. It felt really smart and minimalist and post-modern (whatever that means), and it was completely stupid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now most people are not as dumb as I was, but I still see a lot of cases of Smallthumbnailitis (thankfully, it’s not contagious).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People are browsing your site for one reason and one reason only, to see your work! Don’t hide it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easy fix: bigger thumbnails&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Nuff said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Mistake #4: Small Screenshots&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A close cousin to Mistake #3, this one is even worse. You can’t tell much by looking at a medium-sized screenshot. You want a big image, ideally 100%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, make it easy to go from one image to the next. If you’re using a slideshow, avoid long transitions or fancy effects that slow down the experience&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easy fix: bigger screenshots&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t feel like changing your portfolio’s layout, just stick screenshots in a lightbox, or heck just link to image files. I’d much rather look at a full-size image in an empty web browser than a shrinked and cropped image in a busy page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I’m a fan of how &lt;a href="http://weightshift.com/"&gt;Weightshift&lt;/a&gt; showcases &lt;a href="http://weightshift.com/work/lookout"&gt;their work&lt;/a&gt;: simply big images one after the other, and you just have to scroll down to see more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Mistake #5: Inconsistent Work&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is a biggie. It’s tempting to want to include everything you’ve done in your portfolio including your pre-school crayon drawings, but please don’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a client, the question I’m trying to answer when I’m browsing your portfolio is “can I count on this designer to do great work for me?”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I see 5 great pieces the answer will be “probably yes”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I see 5 great pieces and 5 crappy ones, the answers becomes “maybe, maybe not”. After all, I have no way of knowing if the work you do for me will fall among the good pieces or the bad ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who cares if you’ve worked for 5, 10, or 50 clients before? Quantity doesn’t imply quality, and actually they’re sometimes opposites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easy fix: curate your portfolio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The average client probably has time to check out 6-7 projects tops. So keep your 10 best projects and throw out everything else. I know it’s hard, but it must be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Mistake #6: Lack of Details&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know I’m not hiring you to write a novel, but still, a basic level of details and explanations would be nice. A good designer needs to be a good communicator, and you don’t want to leave a bad first impression by having a portfolio stuck on mute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, some portfolio only show a single screenshot for each project. That’s really not enough to get a good idea of what you did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easy fix: add a couple details&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When did you work on this project? What did you do exactly? How did your work impact the company? Was the client happy?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Show us secondary pages, focus on details, show unused concepts…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even better, write a short case study detailing your design process with sketches, rejected versions, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Mistake #7: Unfocused Portfolio&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is debatable, but I personally feel your portfolio should have a consistent focus. It’s extremely hard to be simultaneously great at web design, logo design, print design, and mobile design, (and if you were you probably would not be reading this article).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, it’s different if you’re creating a single identity across a variety of medias and supports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what I’d avoid is showing a logo for Brand A, a website for Brand B, a t-shirt design for Brand C, etc. If I want a logo/website/t-shirt I’d rather hire someone specialized in that field rather than a jack of all trades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration: line-through;"&gt;Easy&lt;/span&gt; Hard fix: refocus your career&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know, this one isn’t easy by any means. But like Steve Jobs said, “the secret to innovation is saying no to 10000 things”. If you want to be great, you’ll also have to say no and focus your portfolio on a single field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that there’s nothing wrong with cheating: you could always have one portfolio per field, and show the relevant one to potential clients&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you have a portfolio? Do you agree with those tips? Let me know in the comments!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- And if you want to know how you stack up yourself, you can [take this 10-questions quiz](http://blog.folyo.me/folyo-quiz-how-good-is-your-portfolio/) to see how effective your own portfolio site is. --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Portfolio Illustration Credit: &lt;a href="http://www.paykhan.com/"&gt;Paykhan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: this article was originally published on October 25, 2011&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>“How Much Does a Website Cost?” And Other Pricing Questions</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/how-much-does-a-website-cost-and-other-pricing-questions/"/>
    <id>/how-much-does-a-website-cost-and-other-pricing-questions/</id>
    <published>2014-04-23T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-04-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Sacha Greif</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If there’s one thing nobody seems to want to talk about, it’s pricing. Most designers don’t publish their rates, and good luck getting a company to tell you how much they paid for their site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The results of this situation is that it can be pretty hard to know how much to spent on design. Spend too much, and you’ll be accused of wasting money like those $300,000 logos you read about. Spent too little, and you risk ending up with a crappy “designed by my 14 year old nephew” website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I asked 40 of &lt;a href="http://folyo.me/designers"&gt;Folyo’s designers&lt;/a&gt; to answer a couple questions about their pricing strategies, and I hope the results will help you get a better picture of design prices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;A Couple Disclaimers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  All prices are for &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;design only&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, i.e. they don’t include any sort of coding (no HTML, no CSS, no JavaScript, no PHP, etc.).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  The sample size was fairly small (40 designers). Keep this in mind while viewing the results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Folyo only selects experienced and skilled designers. So yes, you can probably find cheaper prices elsewhere (but not better designers!).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Folyo is an international site, and this plays a big role in pricing. A designer in Bangalore will not charge the same as a similarly skilled designer living in San Francisco. That does not mean you should always with the cheaper designer, since other factors (time difference, cultural differences, etc.) will also come into play.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Logos&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure class=""&gt;&lt;img src="/images/blog/budget-logo.png"/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;How much do you charge for a logo?&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The logo is often a startup’s first contact with a designer. You need something that will look good for next month’s big presentation, and you need it fast. But how much will it cost you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although survey results show you can get a logo done for less than $500, I would be careful with such a bargain. A logo will often represent your company for many years to come, and will set the tone for your whole communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, despite what many people think, a logo is not the same thing as a brand. Paying a higher price often means that the designer will not only come up with a logo, but think about what it means and how it can be used in different contexts (online, print, video, etc.) and provide different versions (color, black &amp;amp; white, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So altogether, I would say $1000 is a good starting price point for most logos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;A Homepage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure class=""&gt;&lt;img src="/images/blog/budget-homepage.png"/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;How much do you charge for a homepage?&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The homepage (or landing page) is usually the next step. It’s a more time-consuming job, so the prices are starting to creep up. Depending on the complexity, you’ll pay anything from $500 for a simple teaser to $2000 for a full-featured landing page introducing your product (think &lt;a href="http://basecamphq.com/"&gt;Basecamp’s&lt;/a&gt; homepage).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;A Static Website&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure class=""&gt;&lt;img src="/images/blog/budget-website.png"/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;How much do you charge for a website?&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the classic question every designer dreads. Asking this is like asking an architect how much a house would cost, or a surgeon how much an operation would cost. It all depends on the specifics, so providing a straight answer isn’t easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, assuming that a basic site usually has a homepage, a basic content template, and 1 or 2 additional layouts (pricing page, features page, etc.), we can get an idea of the costs involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Count at least 30 hours of work. The homepage alone will usually eat up 15 hours (and that’s for fast workers), and each additional layout can take 3-5 hours to design. So a basic site will easily reach into the $3000-$5000 range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;A Mobile App&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure class=""&gt;&lt;img src="/images/blog/budget-mobile-app.png"/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;How much do you charge for a mobile app?&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A mobile app is usually simpler than a normal site, but simpler does not mean easier. In fact, the simplification process itself can be the hardest part of the project: which feature do you keep, and which one do you cut? And how will you keep the UI clear and uncluttered?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mobile apps also frequently have higher aesthetic expectations than websites. Although there’s nothing wrong with the default OS controls, it’s now expected that every app will have its own style and every little visual details counts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These factors mean that even with less pages or less contents, mobile apps are not cheaper to design than websites, and $2000 is probably a good place to start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;A Web App&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure class=""&gt;&lt;img src="/images/blog/budget-web-app.png"/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;How much do you charge for a web app?&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Web apps are in a pricing range of their own, with a lot of designers charging $5000 or more. The reason is that there is no such thing as a “small” web app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, the mere fact of supporting user accounts will mean having to design sign up, sign in, and “I forgot my password” screens as well as all the different error states associated with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s more, unlike a static site, a web app must be constantly evolving and pivoting to meet user’s needs. So requirements are hard to pin down, and designers must often plan for unexpected new features being introduced mid-way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And lastly, designing a web app requires a very specific profile, a hybrid UX/visual designer who can both make something look good and make it work great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this explains why this is the most expensive category, and why a $10000 design budget for a web-app is nothing out of the ordinary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These survey results are by no means exhaustive, and keep in mind that every project is different. Still, I hope this article will provide you with some general ballpark figures that will help the next time you have to price a design project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: this article was originally published on September 27th, 2011&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
